atricio López Juri

🛘 (+56) 9 90511003 | 💌 patricio@lopezjuri.com | 🌴 https://lopezjuri.com | 🗖 lopezjuri | 💆 @lopezjuri | 💆 @lopezjuri | 💆 @lopezjuri |

"Computer programs should be understood as a medium and not as an end."

Summary_

Creator of software for humans. Civil Industrial Engineer and Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience building apps and tools. Specialized in architecture, infrastructure, web development, mobile development, Blockchain and a thing or two in Machine Learning. Expert in React.js, Node.js, Ruby and Python. Some experience with Swift, Java, Kotlin, C#, C, and Go.

Digital nomad (worked remotely from +35 countries), biking, foodie, vinyl record collector, music nerd, veggie, and sustainability enthusiast.

Work Experience

ConsenSys.net Remote - Brooklyn, NY, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2018 - PRESENT

- Architect of the TokenFoundry.com platform where we raise more than US\$30 million from the sales of Virtue Poker and FOAM tokens during 2018 in a legal and secure manner. Handled thousand of users and seamlessly incorporated the Ethereum blockchain to handle payments.
- Successfully integrated Know-Your-Costumer services into the platform to prevent money laundry and to blacklist politically exposed users.
- Implemented a versatile quiz system to prevent speculators from purchasing tokens.
- Built a flexible and smart React component library with styled-components and server-side rendering.
- · Successfully instructed and managed team and code-base to ensure a consistent code quality.
- · Built software and systems that integrated with the Ethereum blockchain on the frontend and on the backend.
- Customized pip modules related to OAuth2 and its integration with Django 2.
- Implemented a GraphQL API in a microservice-based architecture for DaisyPayments.com. For asynchronous communication satisfactorily defined Kafka event format and standards.
- Designed and implemented an authentication and authorization system for public API and internal services.

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile - Postgraduate School

Santiago, Chile

ADJUNCT INSTRUCTOR PROFESSOR

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Imparting course: Technologies and Applications of the World Wide Web to 10 professional students.
- Designed from scratch a course with hands-on methodology using Ruby on Rails.
- Lessons about HTTP, business models and basics of web design.
- Recorded programming session about Ruby on Rails, HTML and CSS for the classroom.

ImpulsoDocente Santiago, Chile

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun. 2017 - Nov. 2017

- Design and implementation a mobile to help teachers improve their methodology through videos and feedback.
- Built with React-Native, Redux and Ruby on Rails.
- · Addressed UI/UX concepts and taught product-management methods (Kanban) to clients.

FEUC (Federación de Estudiantes de la Universidad Católica de Chile)

Santiago, Chile

Mar. 2017 - May. 2017

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- · Lead the requirement gathering, design and implementation of a mobile app built with React-Native and Redux with a Express.js, Keystone.js and MongoDB backend.
- Available at https://github.com/open-source-uc/FEUC-mobile and got arround 5000 downloads (iOS & Android).

Booz cl Santiago, Chile

• Implement shopping cart and a search feature with Node.js, MongoDB and jQuery.

· Code refactoring caused several improvements such as increased overall speed and reduced client-side files size.

egghead.io Remote EGGHEAD INSTRUCTOR Mar. 2017 - PRESENT

• Prepare, record and edit an online video course about developing modern JSON WEB APIs with Koa and the latest JavaScript semantics. (Work in progress).

APRIL 6, 2020 LOPEZJURI.COM Mediastream SpA Santiago, Chile

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2016 - Dec 2017

Research about Functions as a Service (FaaS) and evaluate the project of splitting the main monolithic service built with Express.js and MongoDB
to migrate to AWS Lambda and DynamoDB.

- Lead developer at the design and implementation a full-stack application with Koa, Amazon RDS, React, React-Native and Redux with shared code-base between mobile and web with i18n support.
- · Prepare and evaluate technical interviews for senior candidates.
- Improve developer experience (DX) by setting a developer-friendly and debuggable environment.

Núcleo Milenio Centro de Investigación de la Web Semántica - CIWS

Santiago, Chile Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2017

FREELANCE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Lead developer in charge of updating the official website to a new CMS in Node.js and MongoDB from Python and MySQL.

Honors & Awards

2017	Participant, Facebook International Hackathon 2017	California, USA
2017	1st Place, Facebook Chile Regional Hackathon 2017	Santiago, Chile
2017	Honor, Outstanding Student (Engineering at Pontifical Catholic University of Chile)	Santiago, Chile
2014	2nd Place, Start-up Weekend Chile	Santiago, Chile
2014	Best Social App, ChileHack	Santiago, Chile

Presentation

Blockchain Latam Submit CDMX, México

SPEAKER REPRESENTING DAISYPAYMENTS.COM (CONSENSYS)

Jul. 2019

 Introduced DaisyPayments project and talked about the different implementations of subscription-based projects using the Ethereum blockchain.

Blockchain Submit Uruguay

Montevideo, Uruquay

TECHNICAL SPEAKER AT BLOCKCHAIN WORKSHOP

Sept. 2018

• Ethereum workshop: introduction to Web3 with Metamask, Ganache and Solidity.

Wri**ting**

Anatomicis Network: A Cloud-based Educational Software Platform to Enhance Anatomy Teaching in Medical Education

Journal ISI

RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT

Jan. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- Product manager and lead developer of a group of 10 last-year computer science student.
- Requirement gathering, design and implementation of a cloud-based teaching and learning platform with live editing, quizzes and 3D medical
 anatomical models.

Advanced Programming in Python

CONICYT Founded Project

BOOK WRITER

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2016

 Participant in the writing of a book about advanced programming concepts and usage in Python. Wrote a chapter about Webservices and Networking.

Education

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

CIVIL INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER, COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Mar. 2012 - Dec. 2017

- Successfully incorporated GitHub Classroom (classroom.github.com) into many Computer Science courses. Activly participated in the migration of many courses from SVN and Java to modern technologies like JavaScript and Python.
- Led open-source organization for student-developed software. See https://github.com/open-source-uc.
- Local ACM group participant, designer and community manager.
- Recognized teaching assistant.

Extracurricular Activity _____

Alma Máter UC Santiago, Chile

Мемвеr Jan. 2014 - Jan. 2016

Design and development of a mobile app for iOS and Android (Objective-c & Java). It had over 30.000 downloads. It was a free mobile app for
the students of the Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

April 6, 2020 LOPEZJURI.COM